Caleb M. Vatral

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

23 East Elm Ave, Quincy, MA 02170

□ (717) 781-0883 | Saleb.m.vatral@lions.enc.edu | 🕏 www.vatral.net | 🖫 kbvatral | 🛅 caleb-vatral

Professional Summary _

Self-motivated and team oriented individual, who uses a blend of a broad set of academic and technical skills in physics, math, engineering and computer science combined with experience in applied research, software development, and management toward solving real world problems and improving human lives.

Education

Eastern Nazarene College

Quincy, MA

Aug. 2015 - PRESENT

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND MATHEMATICSGPA: 4.0, Expected Graduation: May 2019

Technical Skills

Proficient C++, Python, Java, Responsive Web using W3.CSS, Debian and CentOS Linux, Git/Github

Experienced MATLAB, Apache Spark, PHP, mySQL, InfluxDB, Elasticsearch, LaTex

Research Experience

Data Acquisition PlatformA platform to collect data from remote locations and transmit to a time-series database on a CIS hardened CentOS server for later analysis

Piezo-Magnetic SimulationA MATLAB simulation of the piezo-magnetic effects due to large magnitude earthquakes based on the

results presented in Sasai (1980)

Magnetic Field Sensor

Designed and tested a low magnitude magnetic field sensor for use with measuring disturbances

associated with pre-earthquake signals

Mafia Game Theory Analysis

A game theoretic analysis and accompanying simulation of the strategies and win probabilities for the popular party game, Mafia

popular party game, maiia

Dice RelabelerAn abstract algebraic analysis and calculation of a relabeling of 2 n-sided dice that preserves the original probability distribution

Employment

HCL Technologies Cary, NC

Data Science Intern

May 2018 - Aug 2018

- Developed machine learning models to detect and classify patterns in software performance test data
- Designed REST API for automated analysis, storage, and retrieval of software performance test data

Eastern Nazarene College

Quincy, MA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Jun. 2016 - PRESENT

- Joined with faculty and other students to continue ongoing research in earthquake forecasting full-time during two 10-week summer programs, and part-time during the school year
- Promoted to student manager during summer 2017 research program

Advanced Lab Manager

Aug. 2017 - PRESENT

• Assisted professors in overseeing daily operation in the lab including managing all lab sessions, overseeing all teaching assistants, and facilitating active research projects

PEER TUTOR Aug. 2016 - PRESENT

- Tutored ENC students in coursework for math and physics classes for a variety of skill levels ranging from elementary level to university sophomore level classes
- Promoted to Senior Tutor in Aug. 2017